<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://fury.gl/</id>
  <title>Blog - Posts by Shivam Sahu</title>
  <updated>2023-01-23T18:53:03.543077+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://fury.gl/"/>
  <link href="https://fury.gl/blog/author/shivam-sahu/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <generator uri="https://ablog.readthedocs.org/" version="0.10.33">ABlog</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>https://fury.gl/posts/2022/2022-05-24-my-journey-to-gsoc-2022-shivam.html</id>
    <title>My Journey to GSoC 2022</title>
    <updated>2022-05-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Shivam Sahu</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;section id="my-journey-to-gsoc-2022"&gt;

&lt;section id="about-myself"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About Myself&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi! I’m Shivam, currently pursuing my bachelor’s (expected 2024) in Production and Industrial engineering from the Indian Institute of Technology (IIT) Roorkee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was introduced to the C programming language through the Introduction to programming course in my first year of college. I always liked computers, and I was overwhelmed by printing “hello world” in the terminal. The course continued to teach us data structures and algorithms. It was a lot of fun competing with friends over a programming question. I learned python on my own and did a lot of projects. After learning basic programming, I participated in many hackathons and won some, but lost a lot. Coding was enjoyable, and I knew this was what I wanted to do for the rest of my life.
In my second semester, I learned about open-source, git, and GitHub. I came across some computer graphics enthusiasts in my college; they told me that they created a 2D game engine on their own using OpenGL. This gave me enough motivation to learn OpenGL and basic computer graphics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="intro-to-open-source-and-gsoc"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Intro to Open-Source and GSoC&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In October 2021, I participated in Hactoberfest and completed it successfully. I learned a lot about Free and Open Source Software during this time. I heard about GSoC around this time from one of my seniors and asked him about the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went through the previous year’s accepted organizations list and shortlisted 2-3 organizations. I started contributing to a few projects based on android and kotlin, but I lost interest after some time.
It was about December, and I hadn’t chosen any organization yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I heard about FURY from one of my seniors. I started looking at its docs. Picked up some books from the library to brush up on my concepts of computer graphics. The documentation of FURY is remarkable. I created my &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/fury-gl/fury/pull/520"&gt;first pull request&lt;/a&gt; by improving one of the tutorials, and It got merged in a few days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started looking at the source code of FURY and tried to understand it again. I read the &lt;cite&gt;API reference&lt;/cite&gt; part of FURY docs this time along with the documentation of &lt;cite&gt;VTK&lt;/cite&gt;. I also tried to solve some of the open issues. I created a few pull requests for the same. My first contribution was in the fury &lt;cite&gt;primitive&lt;/cite&gt; class, I created a sphere primitive (inspired by the sphere in Blender).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started looking at bugs and improvements that can be made to the source code and created PRs for the same. During this time I was also learning how computer graphics work from the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCSynd9Z5RdIpKfvTCITV_8A/videos"&gt;UCSC lectures&lt;/a&gt;  &amp;amp; &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://youtube.com/playlist?list=PLPaoO-vpZnumdcb4tZc4x5Q-v7CkrQ6M-"&gt;OpenGL by Victor Gordon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the accepted organizations were announced, I was so happy that FURY got selected this year for GSoC and went straight to the Ideas list. The first project idea was &lt;cite&gt;glTF Integration&lt;/cite&gt;. I heard about the &lt;cite&gt;glTF&lt;/cite&gt; file format before but didn’t know how it works. So I went straight through the reference materials provided on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/fury-gl/fury/wiki/Google-Summer-of-Code-2022-(GSOC2022)"&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;. I read a lot of documentation by the Khronos group. I also tried to implement a basic glTF loader during this time using VTK’s built-in &lt;cite&gt;glTFReader&lt;/cite&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also liked the Improve UI drawing project idea (I had a basic understanding of line drawing algorithms and rasterizations at that time) and thought I’ll make a proposal for that too. After completing my proposal for glTF integration I started my research on this one too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started writing the proposal early so that I could get my proposal reviewed at least once with the project mentors. I almost forgot the fact that I had my end-term examinations at hand (Somehow I managed to pass all of my courses), I kept contributing to the project till the end of April 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code contributions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a class="github reference external" href="https://github.com/fury-gl/fury/pull/520"&gt;fury-gl/fury#520&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a class="github reference external" href="https://github.com/fury-gl/fury/pull/525"&gt;fury-gl/fury#525&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a class="github reference external" href="https://github.com/fury-gl/fury/pull/533"&gt;fury-gl/fury#533&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a class="github reference external" href="https://github.com/fury-gl/fury/pull/547"&gt;fury-gl/fury#547&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a class="github reference external" href="https://github.com/fury-gl/fury/pull/556"&gt;fury-gl/fury#556&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;[&lt;a class="github reference external" href="https://github.com/fury-gl/fury/pull/559"&gt;fury-gl/fury#559&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="the-day"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Day&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May 18: I was a bit anxious since on May 18th the GSoC website was showing my proposal for glTF integration had been rejected. (p.s. maybe it was a bug of some sort that they fixed later on).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May 20: I woke up very early in the morning and started checking the contributor’s profile. I kept checking for new emails but didn’t receive any emails that day. “The result will be announced at 11:30 PM, isn’t it? “ My dad said, It was 8:00 AM IST. I called my friends in the night to join me on discord, I was talking to them and refreshing the GSoC site at the same time. One of my friends shouted that he got selected in NumFocus. I refreshed the page again, my proposal for glTF Integration was accepted. I can’t express what I felt at that moment. I told my friends and my parents, they were happy for me and I got a lot of blessings :). I received an official email the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</content>
    <link href="https://fury.gl/posts/2022/2022-05-24-my-journey-to-gsoc-2022-shivam.html" rel="alternate"/>
    <summary>Hi! I’m Shivam, currently pursuing my bachelor’s (expected 2024) in Production and Industrial engineering from the Indian Institute of Technology (IIT) Roorkee.</summary>
    <category term="google" label="google"/>
    <published>2022-05-24T00:00:00-04:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
